你正被监视着
You are being watched.
政府有一套秘密系统
The government has a secret system--
一台每时每刻都在监视你的机器
A machine that spies on you every hour of every day.
我会知道  因为它是我造的
I know because I built it.
我设计这台机器是为了侦测恐怖活动
I designed the machine to detect acts of terror,
但它却看到了一切
but it sees everything...
它看到了与普通人相关的暴力罪行
Violent crimes involving ordinary people,
像你一样的普通人
people like you,
而政府认为这些罪行无关紧要
crimes the government considered irrelevant.
他们不肯作为  所以我决定插手
They wouldn't act, so I decided I would.
但我需要一个搭档
But I needed a partner--
一个有能力介入其中的人
Someone with the skills to intervene.
因为受到当局追捕  我们只能秘密合作
Hunted by the authorities, we work in secret.
你永远找不到我们
You will never find us.
但不管是被害人还是行凶者
But victim or perpetrator,
只要你的号码被列出来  我们就会找到你
if your number's up, we'll find you.
《疑犯追踪》 第1季 第20集
Person of Interest S01E20 720p HDTV x264
-= 人人字幕 =-
获取
网络监控档案资料  秘密行动
任务：红堡行动
目标：绝密
相关人员：里瑟 约翰
斯坦顿 卡拉
地点：已被篡改
激活图像文件分析系统
恢复被篡改数据
地点：中情局地下网点
摩洛哥得土安
告诉我他在哪儿
Tell me where he is.
中情局地下网点
摩洛哥得土安
我们可以耗上一整晚
We could do this all night.
看着我
Look at me.
你迟早会开口交待的
Sooner or later, you're gonna start talking to me.
我们试一下非语言的交流吧
Let's try some nonverbal communication.
是我  洁西卡
It's me. Jessica, I mean.
我都不知道你还会不会查看这个号码的信息
I don't even know if you check this number.
我想跟你聊聊
I need to talk.
洁西卡  我收到你的信息了
Jessica, I got your message.
你不知道你会不会给我回电
I didn't know if you'd call me back.
我们大概有  有四年没说过话了吧
We haven't talked in-- what, four years?
怎么了
What's wrong?
彼得没什么事吧
Is everything okay with Peter?
没事  他很好  我们都很好
Yeah, he's fine. We're both fine.
我只是
I just...
想找个朋友聊聊
Needed a friend that I could talk to.
肯定有事发生  告诉我
Something's wrong. Talk to me.
你是对的
You know, you were right.
我最后一次见你  在机场的时候
In the airport, the last time I saw you.
你说  到头来  我们都是一个人
You said that, in the end, we were all alone.
我得走了
I should go.
洁西
Jess.
再见  约翰
Bye, John.
我去找你  给我24小时
I'm coming to get you. I'll be there in 24 hours.
等我
Wait for me.
我等你
I'll wait.
最终的关键问题是信任
It all comes down to a matter of trust,
这是一切良好关系的基础
the foundation of any healthy relationship.
我必须知道未来的走向会如何
I just need to know where this is headed.
信任是双方面的  卡特
Trust is a two-way street, Carter.
我知道
I know.
我真的信任你和你的朋友
I do trust you and your friend--
你们俩个我其实最不了解的人
The two people I know the least.
我不确定的是这份工作
It's the job I'm not sure about anymore.
我不知道局里还可以信任谁
I don't know who's got my back on the force.
我肯定我对桌那家伙不干净
I'm pretty sure the guy across the desk from me is dirty.
我会盯着他的
I'll keep my eye on him.
我需要知道更多  约翰
I need to know more, John.
我需要跟你和你朋友一样
I need to know just as much as you and your friend do
了解我们正在解决的案子
about these cases we're working.
那行  我们一起来解决这个案子
Okay, let's work this one together.
那个跟他女友在一起的家伙吗
This guy over here with his girl?
就是他  但那女的不是他的女友
Yeah, only that's not his girl.
那个才是
That's his girl.
你这谎话连篇的无耻小人
You worthless, lying dirtbag!
你被捕了
You're under arrest.
你不是说咱们一起解决案子吗
I thought you said we were working this one together.
没错啊
We are.
你搞定枪手
You're taking care of the shooter,
我保护那劈腿男友免受伤害
and I'm making sure the cheating boyfriend doesn't get hurt.
我感觉挺好啊
Looks fine to me.
里瑟先生  又有新号码了
Mr. Reese, a new number has come in.
你和卡特警探
Have you and Detective Carter
把上个案子解决了吗
wrapped things up on the last one?
刚结束
Just about.
你还没告诉我抓我的原因呢
You still haven't said why you brought me in.
坐下
Sit down.
警方抽奖活动  你中大奖了
Police raffle. You're the big winner.
你的钱在哪里
Where's the money you owe?
什么  我们又不付钱给警察
What? We don't pay the police.
我们付钱给黑帮
We kick back to the mob.
这是过去时了  你现在要付钱给HR
That chapter's closed. You pay HR now.
我的那份在哪里
Where is my money?
-我听不见  -好吧
- I can't hear you. - All right.
我会给你钱
I'll get your money.
但你得跟我去拿
But I gotta take you there.
你跟他去取回来
You go with him and get it.
卡特警探在酒吧说的话
Based on her remarks at the bar,
表明她已经盯上了弗斯科了
sounds like Detective Carter is eyeing Fusco.
我们是不是应该告诉她
Isn't it time we told her
他是在我们的命令下为HR做事的
that he's working with HR at our behest?
时机未到
Not yet.
还说了一堆诚实正直的话
And after all that talk about honesty.
这样对他俩都比较安全
It's safer for both of them.
越少人知道弗斯科的事情
The less people who know about Fusco,
他就越安全
the less danger he's in.
所以你是在保护弗斯科
So now you're protecting Fusco?
我是在保护线人
I'm protecting an asset.
新号码是个什么人
Who's the new number?
汤米・克雷  住在皇后区
Tommy Clay. Lives in Queens.
与妻子乔伊斯结婚十年了
Married ten years to wife Joyce.
有个九岁的儿子
They have a nine-year-old son.
没有任何犯罪记录
No criminal record.
按时缴税
He pays his taxes,
除橄榄球赛季外每周日都去教堂
goes to church every Sunday except during football season.
普通人一个  有什么威胁
An ordinary guy. What's the threat?
我没提这位的职业吗
Did I mention what our number does for a living?
汤米・克雷在格雷灵押运公司工作
Tommy Clay works for Grayling Armored Services.
你去做他手下一名实习生
You'll be a trainee working under him,
今天就是实习日
and today is training day.
小组成员包括一名司机
The crew consists of a driver,
莫里・兰斯顿  在格雷灵工作20年了
Murray Langston, been working at Grayling for 20 years.
汤米是押运员
Tommy is the hopper,
他的工作最危险
the most dangerous position on the crew,
因为他得离开押运车去取送货
because he has to leave the truck to pick up and drop off cargo.
还有一名看守  就是你
And then there's the guard, which is you.
既然机器给出汤米的号码
If the machine gave us Tommy's number...
可能有人正在策划一起抢劫案
Somebody's probably planning a robbery.
押运车抢劫案中有73%
73% of all armored car robberies
是在押运员离开押运车时发生的
happen when the hopper's away from the truck,
如果他们想要袭击你  就会在那时
so if they're gonna hit you, that's when it'll happen.
全球移动通信系统已经连接
GSM link established.
车牌读取器将扫描视线范围内的所有车牌
The plate reader will scan any license in its line of sight.
如果有任何人跟踪或包围押运车
Let us know if anyone's following the truck,
就会马上警示我们
casing it for a robbery.
首先  我们有时不清楚押送什么东西
First thing, we don't always know what we're carrying.
货单上没有吗
It's not on the manifest?
没有注明  约翰  你叫约翰  对吧
Not specifics, John. Your name's John, right?
有些客户会告诉我们是什么
Sometimes a client tells us what it is.
有些不说
Sometimes they don't.
所以每天都得做好被抢的准备
So treat every day as if you're gonna get hit.
受益终生的哲理
That's a good philosophy for life.
莫里  咱们的约翰尼可是位哲人啊
Hey, Murray, Johnny here is a philosopher.
很聪明
Smart.
人家思想肯定深刻
He must have deep thoughts.
别在我值班时被逮住偷懒打瞌睡
Just don't get caught napping on my watch.
这些家伙可没准备好应对真正的威胁  芬奇
These guys aren't ready for any real threat, Finch.
他们的防弹背心是松的
Their vests are loose,
弹夹装得也不对
magazines are stored the wrong way...
我们得搞清威胁是什么
We need to put a face to the threat.
正在交叉确认读取器扫到的所有车牌
Cross-checking every plate from the reader
看看你们有没有被跟踪
to see if they're being followed.
你看上去业务纯熟啊
You almost look like you know what you're doing.
-想我了  -想死了
- Did you miss me? - More than you know.
-替我盯着点  大英雄  -有发现
- Watch my back, hero. - Found something.
有个车牌号今天出现了三次
One plate comes up three times today.
的确有人在跟踪押运车
Someone's following the truck.
我发现有人带着枪过来了
I got guys headed this way with guns.
-在东南角  -快快快快
- Southeast corner. - Go, go, go, go.
发生什么事了  里瑟先生
What's happening, Mr. Reese?
约翰  这里  救命
John, back here! Help!
里瑟先生
Mr. Reese?
笑一个  菜鸟
Smile, rookie!
放松点  约翰尼
Hey, relax, Johnny.
这可不是玩具
That's not a toy, you know.
能杀死人的
You could kill somebody with that thing.
好吧  你们骗到我了
All right, you got me.
假警报  芬奇  只是个恶作剧
False alarm, Finch. It was just a prank.
他们还真可爱
Well, that's endearing.
不幸的是  机器从来不会发出假警报
Unfortunately, the machine never issues a false alarm.
抢劫仍然会发生
The robbery will happen.
而一旦发生抢劫  这伙人的麻烦就大了
And when it does, this crew's in big trouble.
那个人怎么样了
How's our guy doing?
有些进展了  态度有点软化了
I'm making progress, softening him up a bit.
无所谓  你们有新任务了
Doesn't matter. You've been reassigned.
今晚出发  去中国
You head out tonight. China.
不行
No can do.
我得请几天假  家里有急事
I need to take leave--family emergency.
你没有家  里瑟
You don't have any family, Reese,
而且我很确定此情况  非常紧急
and I've been assured that the situation is...urgent.
那就去找其他人
So find someone else.
没时间找其他人了
There's no time to find someone else.
有件东西脱离我们掌控了
We've lost control of a certain item.
当务之急是确保这件东西的安全
Securing it is the highest priority.
-你们明白吗  -明白
- Do you understand? - We understand.
你丢了东西  需要我们找回来
You lost something. You need us to get it back.
我们要找什么
What are we looking for?
你知道"震网"吗
Are you familiar with Stuxnet?
一种电脑病毒
Computer virus.
是我们制造出来用于破坏伊朗核计划的
Built by us to disable the Iranian nuclear program.
你们要找的程序包与此相似
The package you're looking for is similar.
只不过其目标是中国
Only this one targets the Chinese.
对
That's correct.
我们确信国防部里有人把一台
We believe someone inside the Pentagon sold a secure laptop
含源代码的电脑卖给了一家中国公司
containing some of the source code to a Chinese firm.
他们可能研究这些代码用于自己的设备
They may be studying the code to inoculate their devices,
或者修改代码
or they may be modifying the code
来攻击美国的核设施
to target the U.S. nuclear infrastructure.
不管怎样  我们都得拿回电脑
Either way, we need the laptop returned.
-我们要去哪里  -鄂尔多斯
- Where are we going? - Ordos.
这是中国中部的一个企业开发区
It's a company town in the middle of China.
本来准备建成百万人口的地区
It was built for a million people,
可是投资的公司倒闭了
only the company that built it folded.
现在成了"鬼城"  没有居民
It's a ghost town. No residents.
所以你们坐飞机到北京
So you're gonna fly into Beijing.
以外交作掩护  两周时间收集情报
Diplomatic cover, two weeks to gather intel,
然后开始行动
then you're going in.
这台电脑非同小可  需极为谨慎
The laptop has to be handled with extreme caution,
所以不准使用电话  不许使用任何网络设备
so no phones. No network devices of any kind.
这个软件会侵入任何开放的通信线路
This software will exploit any open communication channel.
明白了吗
Understood?
走吧
Let's go.
里瑟
Reese.
还有件事
One more thing.
你拿到程序包之后
After you secure the package,
清除斯坦顿特工
You're to retire agent Stanton.
你让我杀了我的搭档吗
You're telling me to kill my partner?
我们拦截到了她和这个人的
We've intercepted unauthorized communications
未授权通信
between her and this man,
真主党的中间人
A go-between for Hezbollah.
有大笔资金汇入了一个海外账户
Large deposits into an off-shore account.
她叛变了
She's been compromised.
身为她的搭档  你应该意识到
As her partner, you should have noticed.
我们要自己清理门户  里瑟
We clean up our own mess, Reese.
你知道的
You know that.
完成这次任务  你想休假多久都行
You get this done, you can have all the leave you need.
明白吗
You understand?
我是洁西卡  你错过我喽
This is Jessica. You missed me.
请留言
Leave a message.
在找什么
What are we looking at?
我黑入了押运车公司的服务器
I've hacked the truck company's servers
找到了你今天的路线
and retrieved your route for today.
知道押运车的取货位置
If I know the pickup locations,
就能缩小可能发生抢劫的地域范围
I can narrow down where the robber might hit.
卡特给你
Carter get back to you
跟踪我们的车牌信息了吗
on the plate of the car following us?
还没
Not yet.
莱奈尔  好久没你消息了
Lionel, you've been quiet.
我都开始担心你了
I was getting worried.
是啊  跟着林奇置身于狂野西部了
Yeah, it's like the wild, wild west out here with Lynch.
因为我们抓到了以利亚  HR现在资金短缺
HR's getting short on funds since we took down Elias,
所以他要挥舞大棒收保护费呢
so he's chasing down street money with a baseball bat.
好像我道上的敌人还不够多似的
Not like I didn't have enough enemies on the street.
继续收集情报
Keep gathering intel.
我们得知道他们的头目是谁
We need to know their leadership.
拿下剩下的那些人
Take down the remaining players.
至少我费的这些劲赚到钱了
At least I'm getting a cut for my efforts.
你想要我怎么处理这些钱
What do you want me to do with the money?
我只关心HR  弗斯科  不关心钱
I care about HR, Fusco, not the money.
你自己看着办吧
What you do with it is your business.
-爸爸  -小子
- Hey, dad. - Hey, buddy.
不如等你训练结束后
What do you say I take you after practice,
我带你去买点新装备吧
get you some new gear?
-真的吗  -当然  有何不可
- Really? - Yeah, why not?
你发来的照片看起来很像是
These pictures you sent over look suspiciously like the ones
我们的自动车牌读取器拍下的
from our automated license plate readers.
你用了我的警车吗
Did you take one off my car?
没  没用你的
Well, no... not your car.
我就装作没听见好了
I'll pretend I didn't hear that.
反正  车牌属于一辆95年的雪佛兰
Anyway, the plate belongs to a '95 gray Chevrolet van,
登记在一名72岁的交通管理员名下
registered to the 72-year-old transit authority administrator.
72岁的人追踪武装车吗
A 72-year-old that's casing an armored car?
所以我做了点调查
That's why I dug a little deeper.
原来车主的外甥  弗兰克・罗威尔
Apparently the owner's nephew, Frank Lowell,
在两个月前被释放
was paroled two months ago.
他05年因持械抢劫被捕
Busted back in '05 for armed robbery,
其同伙米克・诺顿也同时被捕  去年被释放
along with buddy, Mick Norton, released last year.
照片已经发给你了
I just sent the photos to you.
你对付这两个人可能需要帮助
You might need help with these two.
我搞得定
I got it covered.
睡好你的美容觉了吗  美人
Hey, did you catch up on your beauty sleep, sunshine?
不算很好
Not so much.
做了个噩梦  梦到我和一群小丑一起工作
I had a nightmare I was working with a bunch of clowns.
没错  那是汤米
Yeah, well, that's Tommy.
他总是到处扮小丑
He's always clowning around.
那是汤米的妻子吗
Is that tommy's wife?
说到母老虎
Talk about a ball buster.
我把离婚周年纪念日
I celebrate the anniversary of my divorce
当新年一样庆祝
like it's new year's eve.
干这个工作已经压力够大了
This job is stressful enough.
没人想回家了还要听唠叨  免了
No one needs that nonsense to come home to, no.
婚姻就是折腾
Marriage is a racket.
还想再来吗  约翰
Back for more, John?
我看到莫里又翘了早上的普拉提课
I see Murray here skipped his morning Pilates again.
是啊  我开始新的法式土司养身法了
Yeah, I'm starting a new French toast regimen.
这位朋友是谁啊  汤米
Who's your friend, Tommy?
约翰新来的  艾希莉
John the newbie, Ashley.
他来熟悉下工作  我可是新人训练大师
He needs to learn the ropes, and I'm the ropes master.
你要吃什么  亲爱的
What are you having, hon?
能打包的东西
Something you can put in the bag.
我总是吃煎蛋三明治
I always stick with a fried egg sandwich.
是啊  可那是因为你不认识菜单上其他字
Yeah, but that's because you can't read the rest of the menu.
咖啡就好  谢谢
Coffee's fine, thank you.
手镯真漂亮啊
Whoa, that's a nice bracelet, huh?
那个幸运的小子是谁  艾希莉
Who's the lucky stiff, Ashley?
不是  这是我祖母送我的礼物
It's nothing. It's just a present from my grandma.
她品位真不错
She's got good taste.
我给你的三明治
I threw in a little extra hot sauce
多加了辣酱  汤米
with your sandwich, Tommy.
汤米  多加了辣酱啊
Whoa, Tommy, you got a little extra hot sauce, huh?
我可是已婚男人了
Hey, married man over here.
是啊  更像是半个男人
Yeah, more like half a man.
好了  美女们  该上班了
All right, ladies, time to punch in.
走吧
Let's go.
你以前干什么的  约翰
So what's your story, John?
在别的地方做过保安吗
You ever been a security guard anywhere else?
-偶尔  -商场保安吗
- Here and there. - Mall cop?
超市保安吗
Supermarket stiff?
差不多吧
Something like that.
我只是想说  这儿可不是沃尔玛
All I'm saying is, this ain't Walmart.
你之前被抢过吗
You ever been robbed before?
就一次
Once.
我和我搭档在转移一台自动取款机里的钱
My partner and I were servicing this ATM.
两个人带着枪出现
These two guys came up with guns.
我想当英雄来着  穿着防弹背心中了两枪
I tried to be a hero. Took two in the vest.
他们逃走了
They got away.
我断掉了几根肋骨  拿到了危险津贴
I got a set of cracked ribs and a bump in hazard pay.
别紧张  大多数任务都像现在这样
Don't worry. Most of the job is like this,
坐在运输车里
You know? Sitting around in traffic,
尽量不晕车就行了
trying not to get carsick.
如果子弹不来找你  无聊就来找你
If the bullets don't get you, the boredom will.
我已经把灰色货车的车牌做了标记
I've just flagged the gray van's license plate,
所以只要它一出现
so the plate reader will alert us
车牌读取器就会向我们示警
just as soon as it appears again.
我还调查了一下
I've also been able to retrieve some information
你们今天要去的公司
from the company's database about your stops today.
第一州立银行
One State Bank.
你们负责运输的是
Your cargo is
他们职员的退税
their employees' tax returns.
下一站  海力根公司
Your next stop, Heliogem Incorporated.
但运输品仅是一些工业用的低端宝石
But the shipment is just low-grade stones for industrial use.
再下一站  里根医疗器材公司
Next stop is Regan Medical Supply,
主要产品是  心脏起搏器  还有其他的
Manufacturers of... pacemakers, among other things.
这东西相当贵
Those are expensive,
很难随意在黑市上买卖
hardly something you can fence on the street.
-朝你过来了  莫里  -等一下
- Heading your way, Murray. - Hang on.
内部货单显示你们提取的
The internal manifest shows that you're actually
其实是心脏起搏器的原材料
picking up raw materials for pacemakers.
铂金
Platinum.
铂金的标价是
Platinum is priced at
一盎司1千6百美金
$1,600 an ounce.
大概是一磅2万5千美金
That approximately $25,000 a pound.
那么50磅就是
There's 50 pound--
里瑟先生  这些箱子价值125万美金
Mr. Reese, those cases are worth about $1.25 million.
这一定就是目标了
That must be the target.
哥们儿
Wow, bro.
放轻松
You need to relax.
快点  莫里  走吧
Come on, Murray, let's go.
我不明白
I don't understand.
劫案应该在那一站发生才对啊
The robbery should have taken place at the last stop.
你们剩下的地点只有  德维特杂货店了
All you've got left is Dewitt Grocery.
这相比之下很不合理
That's inconsequential compared--
待在这儿
Stay here.
快点  我们走
Come on, let's go.
里瑟先生  里瑟先生
Mr. Reese? Mr. Reese?
■
获取
网络监控档案资料
秘密行动
任务：已被篡改
目标：已被篡改
相关人员：已被篡改
地点：已被篡改
激活图像文件分析系统
恢复被篡改数据
任务：未命名
目标：无档案记录
相关人员：无档案记录
地点：中国鄂尔多斯
阿尔法小队就位
Alpha Team is on-site.
他们有他们的任务  我们有我们的
They've got their orders, and we've got ours.
中国鄂尔多斯
事成之后通知你
I'll let you know when it's done.
我们在这儿分开
This is where we part ways.
你们得孤身进入
You're going in alone.
情报说你们只会遇到轻微抵抗
Intel says you can expect only light resistance.
我接到命令  没收你们所有的通信设备
I've got orders to confiscate any comm devices you have.
我们要抽身的时候怎么发信号
How do we signal for extract?
用这个  红外化学灯
Use these. Ir chem lights.
直升机会在登陆区跟你们会合
A helo's going to meet you at the LZ.
你们有72小时
You've got 72 hours.
我们接到的指令是自行退出
We got orders to make our own way back.
禽流感一定是为了掩人耳目
Bird flu must have been a cover.
这里被隔离起来
The place is under quarantine.
以吓走当地人
Scaring the locals.
用来防范电脑病毒也太兴师动众了
A lot of precautions for a computer virus.
我感觉他们没有说出全部内情
I'm not sure we're being told the whole story here.
"我们从不质疑"
"Ours is not to reason why."
这不是你教我的吗
Isn't that what you taught me?
我还以为你没听进去呢
And I thought you weren't listening.
看来我们来迟了一步
Looks like we're a little late to the party.
里瑟先生
Mr. Reese.
Mr. Reese?
身份查实了吗
You got that I.D. running?
里瑟先生
Mr. Reese?
-怎么了  医生  -他快不行了
- What's happening, doctor? - We're losing him.
三号手术室准备
Standing by O.R. three.
-血压70/52  -心跳停止
- Bp 70/52. - I'm getting no pulse at all.
好吧  宣布死亡
All right, I'm calling.
看来你需要帮助
Looks like you could use some help.
来  扶住我
Come on. Hold on to me.
肋骨撞伤
Bruised ribs.
子弹击中防弹背心  伤到皮肤
Bullet hit the vest, broke the skin.
这样就算你很走运了
You're lucky it's not worse.
我不应该帮汤米
I wasn't supposed to help Tommy.
我应该阻止他的
I was supposed to stop him.
内部人作案一般都是
Yeah, well, most inside jobs,
内应悄悄留门接应  然后拿到提成
guy leaves a door open, takes a cut.
用这种爆炸的手段
Guy comes out blasting like this,
他最好有周全的逃离策略
he better have a well-thought-out exit strategy.
这家伙还有个家呢
This guy's got a family.
是啊  我们现在正在搜查他家
Yeah, we're searching his house right now,
把他老婆带回来询问了
bringing his wife in for questioning.
他肯定有同伙
He's got to be working with somebody.
他需要一个销赃的人
Well, he needs a fence.
他得把那些铂金脱手
He's still got to flip that platinum.
怎么了
Yeah?
他正和我在一起
He's right here with me.
感谢上帝
Thank God.
我追踪到你电话信号在一家医院  但是
I tracked your phone to a hospital, but...
-我不知道  -没事  哈罗德
- I didn't know-- - It's okay, Harold.
我还活着呢
I'm still ticking.
我在看我们装在
Well, I'm watching the feed that
押运车内部的监控器传回的视频
we piggybacked off the internal camera in the truck.
汤米还有另一部手机
Tommy had a second phone.
他在抢劫前发了一条信息
Sent a text just before the robbery.
肯定是在向其他劫匪发信号
He must have been signaling the other robbers.
我们得找到他  芬奇
Well, we gotta track him, Finch.
我得在汤米害更多人前阻止他
I've got to stop Tommy before he hurts anyone else.
当我是孩子的时候  常来这儿玩游戏
Used to play pickup games here when I was a kid.
你还天真烂漫过
You were a kid?
打了不少架  学会了怎么用拳头
Got into some fights. Learned how to use my fists.
我要你做点事
I need you to do something.
什么事
What?
去布鲁克林取点东西
Pick up something in Brooklyn.
详情另行通知
Details to follow.
只许成功不许失败
Failure's not an option.
我知道你明白我的意思
I know you understand what I'm saying.
你丈夫在哪儿  克雷太太
Where's your husband, Mrs. Clay?
我不知道
I don't know.
我一整天都没和汤米联系过了
I haven't talked to Tommy all day.
是啊  他可忙了
Yeah, well, he's been busy.
抢劫了自己的押运车  枪击了两个人
He robbed his own truck, shot two people,
你还没接到他的电话
and you still haven't heard from him.
汤米是个好人
Tommy is a good person.
他从没提过要从押运车偷东西
He's never talked about stealing anything off a truck.
真的吗
Is that right?
我们在你家找到了这个
Found this in a closet in your house.
这是装钻石手链的
It's for a diamond tennis bracelet,
汤米两天前运送的货物中的一件
part of a shipment Tommy delivered two days ago.
不过我猜这只是从押运车上掉下来的
But I guess it just fell off the truck.
什么钻石
A diamond what?
汤米没给过你手链  是吧
Tommy didn't give you a bracelet, did he?
汤米有外遇
Tommy's having an affair,
如果我们能找到小三  就能找到他
so if we find his girlfriend, we'll find him.
我进度比你超前  警探
I'm way ahead of you, detective.
-续杯吗  -当然
- Top off? - Absolutely.
有发现吗  芬奇
Anything yet, Finch?
是的  事实上
Yes, as a matter of fact.
同一个号码一小时内
One number in her call history
在她通讯记录里出现了好几次
comes up several times in the last hour.
没有来电显示
No name on the account.
也许是汤米用的一次性手机
Could be Tommy on a burner phone.
-你能追踪到他吗  -看我的
- Can you track him? - We'll see.
我从艾希莉的照片记录中发张艳照给他
I'm texting him an alluring photo from Ashley's archive,
希望能尽快有答复吧
Hoping it'll get a quick response.
当他打开信息
When he opens the message,
文件里的间谍程序木马
A spyware Trojan embedded in the file
会把他GPS的位置发给我
will send his GPS coordinates.
很好
Good.
里瑟先生  汤米的一次性手机有动静了
Mr. Reese, I got a hit on Tommy's burner phone.
他最近一次使用是在罗伊斯汽车旅馆
He last checked it from the Royce Motel.
汤米不在这里
Tommy's not here.
看来他的劫匪同伙们都死了
It looks like the robbers that were with him are dead.
他是在杀人灭口
He's cutting his ties to the heist,
独吞赃物
keeping the loot for himself.
尸体还有余温
Bodies are still warm.
汤米还没走
Tommy's still here.
别动
Hold it.
这可不是禽流感
So much for the bird flu.
这些人都被枪杀的
These people were gunned down.
他们是软件工程师  不是士兵
Software engineers, not soldiers.
为什么要杀他们
Why kill them?
还有一个活口  没死透
We got a live one here. Mostly alive.
求你给我一点东西
让我止痛
发生什么了
他们来
把它拿走了
拿走了什么
机器
他说什么
What did he say?
说他想要止痛
He said he wanted something for the pain.
杀手行动利落
Action here was clean.
迅速
Fast.
可能是海陆侦察队或雇佣杀手干的
BMR recon team maybe or hired guns.
好像是程序包
Looks like the package.
为什么杀死所有人  偏偏却留下它
Why kill all these people and leave it behind?
或许他们把文件复制了
Maybe they copied it.
或者替换了  然后故意留给我们
Or altered it and left it for us to find.
天黑之前直升机都没法来接我们
Helo won't be able to pick us up till dark.
我们得到安全地带准备撤离
We need a safe place to wait for extract.
还要提防谁吗
Safe from whom?
我们现在可是这儿唯一的活人
We're the only living people in this city.
你先请
After you.
我刚刚应该开枪  以后的日子就轻松了
I should've shot you and simplified my life.
倍感压力了吗  莱奈尔
Pressure getting to you, Lionel?
-你来这儿干嘛  -林派我来的
- Why are you here? - Len sent me over.
要我跟一个叫克雷的家伙见面
Presupposed to meet a guy by the name of Clay.
HR也想参与抢劫案的分赃吗
HR looking for a cut of the heist?
整起抢劫案就是HR发起的
HR helped set up the heist.
他们亲自挑的人
They hand-picked the shooters.
我是来拿回属于HR的那份
I'm supposed to be picking up their cut.
那你有麻烦了  汤米・克雷早跑了
You've got a problem. Tommy Clay's long gone.
抛下了他的同伙
And he left his buddies behind.
我靠
Ah, jeez.
不把铂金拿回去
I don't come back with the platinum,
HR会觉得是我私吞了
HR's gonna think I took it.
那我就死定了
That makes me a dead man.
你得帮我
You gotta help me with this.
当初可是你让我跟那帮人打交道的
You got me working with these guys in the first place.
我会找到汤米
I'll find Tommy.
-你可以走了  -我走
- Now off you go. - Off I go?
我怎么跟HR交代啊
What am I gonna tell HR, huh?
你是个撒谎高手  警探  记得吗
You're a talented liar, detective, remember?
不然我当初干嘛选你
That's why I picked you.
-你在吗  芬奇  -永远都在
- You there, Finch? - Always.
如果你要问汤米在哪  我不知道
If you're calling to ask where Tommy is, I don't know.
他一离开汽车旅馆就把手机毁了
He destroyed his phone as soon as he left the motel.
除手机外还有别的信息吗
Get anything off the phone?
只有一条
Only that
他几乎什么都用"艾希莉"做密码
he uses the name Ashleyas a password on almost everything.
那个餐厅的艾希莉吗
Ashley from the diner?
-真是深情一片  -相互的
- Must be love. - And it's mutual.
我查了她信用卡的交易记录
I checked her credit card transactions.
她刚买了价值超过五千美元的
She just charged over $5,000 worth
路易威登行李箱
of Louis Vuitton suitcases.
她准备跟汤米一起逃跑
She's running off with Tommy.
我去找她  你去追查汤米的下落
I'll try to intercept her, and you try to track down Tommy.
我不确定这种人值得我们保护  里瑟先生
I'm not sure he deserves our protection, Mr. Reese.
他冷血地杀了自己的朋友
He killed his friend in cold blood
还给我背后来了一枪
and shot me in the back.
我想的可不是保护他
I wasn't thinking of protecting him.
你说这个家伙干掉了两个我们的人
You're telling me this guy killed two of our men
还带着铂金跑了
and took off with all the platinum?
大概是新手的运气吧
Maybe it's beginner's luck.
跃跃欲试啊  警探
Getting ambitious, detective?
想耍花招吗
Working an angle?
你要是不信我  自己去汽车旅馆看
Look, you don't believe me, go to the hotel.
那儿摆着两具死尸还有两个空箱子
There's two dead bodies and two empty cases.
要耍花招  弗斯科
Thing about angles, Fusco,
不管你怎么耍  结果都一样
You add 'em up, always comes out the same.
我们站在这儿扯得越久
You know, the longer we stand here talking,
那个汤米小子
the further distance this kid Tommy
拿着钱跑得就越远
is gonna put between us and our money.
就算你没摆我一道
Assuming you're not shining me on,
那小子可能藏铂金的地方就那些
there's only so many places he could fence the platinum.
都在哪儿  我们分头找
So where are they? We'll divvy them up.
不行  我们一起去
No. We do it together.
这样我才能盯住你
That way I can keep an eye on you.
-真是漫长的一天  -是啊
- Such a long day. - I know.
现在只想回家休息
Just want to go home.
-电话联系  -回头聊  拜
- Call me. - Talk to you later. Bye.
你好  艾希莉
Hello, Ashley.
-滚出去  -不
- Get out of my car. - No.
对不起
Sorry.
你是汤米的同事
You work with tommy.
你想干嘛
What do you want?
手镯真的不错
You know, that is a nice bracelet.
不是祖母给你的  对不对
Grandma didn't give it to you, did she?
我知道是谁给你的
But I know who did.
他在哪儿  汤米在哪儿  艾希莉
Where is he? Where's Tommy, Ashley?
我不知道
I don't know.
真的  我不知道
Honestly, I don't.
什么意思
What do you mean?
我本该在这里跟他见面
I'm supposed to wait for him here.
三个小时前他就该来接我的
He was gonna pick me up three hours ago,
所以要么他出了事  要么...
So either something terrible has happened to him or...
他抛下我走了
he's gone without me.
你们之前的计划是什么
What was your plan?
我就不该相信他
I never should have believed him.
他说他会带我逃离这一切
He said he was going to take me away from all this,
我们一起去墨西哥卡波海滩
and we were gonna go to Cabo together.
至少你得到了不错的路易威登包
Well, at least you got your nice Louis Vuitton bags.
原来汤米是真正的操纵者  芬奇
This Tommy's turned out to be a real operator, Finch.
这会儿  他把所有人都甩下了
And right now, he's putting everyone in his rearview mirror.
你有什么消息吗
You got anything?
汤米是个习惯主义者
Tommy's a creature of habit.
所有密码都是一样的
Uses the same password for everything.
他的另一个习惯就是买塞米托一次性手机
His other habit is buying Symetel burner phones.
塞米托一直都在批量连贯销售号码
Symetel leases their numbers in consecutive blocks.
我写了一个脚本
I wrote a script
在所有新号码中搜索以"艾希莉"为密码的
trying the password "Ashley" on all new numbers,
找到了他的新号码
And I found his new phone.
以及他收到的一封网页语音邮件  你听
Along with web-based voicemail message he received. Listen.
收到你的信息了
Got your message.
阿图罗拳击俱乐部  一小时后在那儿见
Arturo's Boxing Club. I'll be there in an hour.
我猜他就是汤米的铂金买家
My guess is this is the man Tommy's selling the platinum to.
这条消息四十五分钟前接收的
Message was received 45 minutes ago.
我就去  把地址发给卡特
On my way. Give Carter the address.
我会把汤米绑起来  交给她
I'll wrap Tommy up, give him to her.
什么事
What's up?
那个押运车抢劫犯有下落了
Got a location on the armored truck robber--
在皇后区的阿图罗拳击俱乐部
Arturo's Boxing Club in Queens.
-约翰已经上路了  -卡特
- John's on his way there. - Carter.
警探  你听到了吗
Detective, did you hear me?
等等  中情局来找我了
Hang up. The CIA's onto me.
这回你们得靠自己解决了
You'll have to handle this on your own.
斯诺特工还有  这位不知叫什么名字的
Agent Snow and... whatever your name is.
-我叫伊万斯  -你们来干嘛
- Evans. - What do you want?
过来打个招呼  看看你怎么样
To say hi, see how you are.
我很好  你们来干嘛
I'm fine. What do you want?
我知道你在跟联调局谈里瑟的事
We know that you're talking to the FBI about Reese.
这犯法吗
Is there a law against that?
历史一次又一次地证明
As they've proven time and again,
联调局无法胜任涉及国家安全的事
the FBI cannot be trusted with matters of national security.
不要跟唐纳利特工谈
Do not talk to Agent Donnelly.
你指我们那位朋友的事吧
Oh, you mean about our mutual friend.
为什么  你怕唐纳利会先于你们找到他吗
Why, you're afraid Donnelly's gonna get to him first?
你到底怕他告诉唐纳利什么
What exactly are you worried he's gonna tell him?
小心点  警探
Be careful, detective.
我们就快抓到约翰了
We're closing the net on John.
他很会藏  但我很会找
He's good at hiding, but I'm good at finding people.
当我找到他
And when I do,
你就会后悔当初选错边站了
you're gonna want to be on the right side of this thing.
不要跟唐纳利谈
Don't talk to Donnelly.
里瑟先生  恐怕你得孤军奋战了
Mr. Reese, I'm afraid you're on your own now.
你中情局的老同事刚刚去找卡塔了
Carter just had a visit from your old colleagues in the CIA.
收到
Copy that.
谁在那儿
Who is it?
汤米
Hey, Tommy.
约翰尼
Johnny.
这下是回敬你在我背后开枪
That's for shooting me in the back.
这下是为了莫里
That's for Murray.
铂金在哪儿
Where's the platinum?
我不会说的
I'm not telling you.
你逃不掉的
You won't get away with this.
你不知道你对付的是什么人
You have no idea who you're dealing with.
你认为吗
You think?
我跟那些混球一样聪明
I'm just as smart as every one of those jerks.
汤米  你是清白人
Tommy, you were clean.
你有妻子  有孩子
You had a wife, a kid,
没有前科
no prior record.
但你都弃之不顾了  为什么
But you threw it all away. Why?
因为过去十年里的每一天
Because every day for the last ten years,
我都在保护别人的钱
I've protected other people's money,
但我却一无所有  一无所有
and I have nothing show for it. Nothing.
所以你觉得这世界欠你的  对吗
So the world owes you, is that it?
不  不欠我
No, it doesn't.
我想了很久才弄明白
I figured that one out. Took a while.
你知道我还弄明白了什么吗
You know what else I figured out?
运着那些钱
Hauling around all that money--
伸手一拿就是你的
You get what you take.
-所以我拿了我的  -这是不可能的
- So I'm taking mine. - That's not gonna happen.
你的这一自我想法  汤米
The thing about striking out on your own, Tommy,
只会让你自我毁灭
is that's usually how you end up.
是吗
Yeah?
我感觉你所言有理
I think you got that just about right.
嗨  汤米
Hi, Tommy.
嗨  宝贝
Hi, babes.
帮我摆平这位忧郁王子  好吗
Help me get rid of this mope, will you?
花了数十年研发完美的营养口粮
Spent decades trying to invent the perfect nutritional ration.
还是难以下咽
And it's still inedible.
这些被淘汰只是时间问题
It's just a matter of time before this is all obsolete.
我们还是得吃
We'll still have to eat.
我不是说吃的
I'm not talking about the mres.
卫星代替了监控小组
You got satellites replacing surveillance teams,
无人飞机代替了战斗机飞行员
drones replacing fighter pilots.
所以我们都过时无用了吗
So we've outlived our usefulness?
我们会被一个按钮换掉  对吗
We'll be replaced by a push of a button, is that it?
你认为呢
What do you think?
我认为我们还在这儿
I think we're still here.
你想过我们是怎样得到情报的吗
You ever wonder where we get our intel?
我以为你从不问问题
I thought you didn't ask questions,
只服从命令
just followed orders.
我可没说过这容易做到
I never said it was easy.
天要黑了
Sun's setting.
该走了
Time to go.
喂
Yeah?
我们的朋友遇上麻烦了
Our friend is in a bit of trouble.
我们需要你帮忙
We need your help.
谁的电话
Who are you talking to?
我现在很忙  没法讲电话
I'm busy right now. I can't talk.
我前妻
My ex.
现在告诉我  是谁在追我们
Now you're going to tell me who's coming for us.
铂金在哪儿  汤米
Where's the platinum, Tommy?
拳击台下面
It's over there under the ring
在装手套的箱子里
in that box with the gloves.
原来是艾希莉出主意  你动手
So Ashley's the brains, and you're the muscle.
是吗  汤米
Is that right, Tommy?
我们是搭档
We're partners.
是她说服你动手的  是吗
She convinced you it was time to make your move, didn't she?
她说你理应得到更多
She said you deserve more from life.
别理他  汤米
Ignore him, Tommy.
-我很抱歉  -抱歉
- I'm so sorry. - Sorry?
你为什么抱歉
What are you sorry for?
大鱼吃小鱼的规则
The law of the fishes.
我早该知道的
I should've seen it coming.
你在说什么
What are you talking about?
我所帮助的人  我从不知道
The people I help, I never know
他们是被害人还是行凶者
if they're gonna be the victim or the perp,
但我觉得  这回  你两者都是
but I think, this time, you're both.
现在如何
Now what?
你认为你能走出这里
You think you're going to walk out of here
从此过上幸福的生活吗
and live happily ever after?
你面对的是一群十恶不赦的坏人
You're dealing with some very bad people.
闭嘴
Shut up.
现在  你手上有他们要的
Right now, you have what they want,
他们不拿到东西绝对不会罢休
And they won't stop until they get it.
你第一次开枪杀人吗
First time you shot someone?
第一次总是很难
First one's hard.
你可能已经考虑过一阵子
You've probably been thinking about it for a while,
做好了思想准备
psyched yourself up.
但第二枪会更艰难
But the second one can even be harder.
都在那儿吗
All there?
-是的  -知道不
- Yeah. - What do you know?
原来你没撒谎
You weren't lying after all.
瞧瞧这是谁啊
Well, look who's here...
卡特的守护天使
Carter's guardian angel.
就知道我们早晚有再见的时候
Thought our paths might cross again at some point.
我看这次轮到你被挂在楼外边了
I think it's your turn to hang off the side of a building.
别管他了  我们赶快走吧
Hey, forget him, let's get out of here.
说得对
You're right.
我是想再玩玩的
I was gonna have some fun.
不过还是一枪解决吧
But I'll just shoot him.
里瑟先生  你还好吧
Mr. Reese, everything okay?
芬奇  我们要用到你的后车箱了
Finch, we're going to need your trunk.
不用  我能摆平
No, I got this one.
我是用她的枪打的
I shot him with her gun.
能轻易布置成
Simple enough to make it look
好像林奇把整件事搞砸的
like Lynch botched the whole thing.
你越来越擅长了  莱奈尔
You're getting good at this, Lionel.
我一直很擅长
I was always good at this.
不然你当初干嘛选我
That's why you picked me in the first place.
记得吗
Remember?
该结束了  约翰
Time to wrap this up, John.
听着  卡拉  有件事要告诉你
Listen, Cara, there's something you need to know--
对不起  约翰
Sorry, john.
我也不想
Nothing personal.
他们告诉我你已经叛变了
They told me you've been compromised,
身为你的搭档  我得清理门户
that as your partner, it was my mess to clean up.
有什么好笑的
Something funny?
我接到了相同的命令
I got the same orders as you.
派我们来的人并不是想让我们取回程序包
Whoever sent us here doesn't want us to retrieve the package.
而只是想确认它被毁掉了
They want to confirm it's destroyed.
他们希望任何与之有接触的人都被毁掉
They want everyone who had contact with it destroyed.
而你刚刚给了他们信号
And you just gave them a beacon.
-目标锁定  -可以发射了
- Target locked. - You are clear to engage.
发射
Engaging.
这次我们做成了什么事吗
Did we actually accomplish anything here?
我们阻止了汤米杀人后逍遥法外
We stopped Tommy from getting away with murder.
也算做成点事
That's something.
他本来就没机会逃生  不是吗
He didn't stand a chance, did he?
想当坏人的麻烦就在于
Problem with trying to be the bad guy...
总是有更坏的人
is there's always someone worse.
音频拦截
会话分析
语言识别
我们有里瑟的线索了
Hey, we got a lead on Reese.
来自北朝鲜的情报
An asset in North Korea:
一个不同政见组织在2010年5月帮一名
A dissident group helped an injured CIA operative
负伤的中情局探员从鄂尔多斯附近的小镇逃脱
escape from a town near Ordos, China, May 2010.
鄂尔多斯  肯定是我们要找的人
Ordos? Must be our guy.
情报指向一个开曼群岛外的银行账户
The asset pointed us to a bank account out of Grand Cayman.
两天前该账户在皇家曼哈顿酒店
Same account was accessed two days ago
对面的一家银行有过操作
at a bank across the street from the Royal Manhattan Hotel.
那边见
Meet me there.
你好  马克
Hello, Mark.
请坐
Have a seat.
我们有点事要处理了
We have some catching up to do.
《疑犯追踪》 第1季 第20集
Person of Interest S01E20 720p HDTV x264
-= 人人字幕 =-